Guide to the Woman Suffrage and Women's Rights Collection, 1866–1989
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Woman Suffrage and Women's Rights Collection
1866-1989
Vassar College
3.2 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of petitions, speeches, correspondence, publications, scrapbooks, and broadsides relating to the struggles for woman suffrage and other women's rights. Includes documents relating to debates over the suffrage issue at Vassar College.
Scope and Content Note
Materials relating to woman suffrage include a petition to the New York State Assembly signed by Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. Anthony, Henry Blackwell, and Lucy Stone, 1866; Stanton's speech "Solitude of Self," 1892; speeches by Clara M. Hill and Dr. Howard B. Kelly; correspondence of Henry MacCracken on suffrage and Vassar College, 1917-1918; publications of the National American Woman Suffrage Association, and other suffrage organizations; scrapbooks of clippings, 1906-1917; and other programs, songs, plays, speeches, broadsides, government documents, and clippings on woman suffrage in the United States and abroad. Materials relating to women's rights include publications, programs, and other printed materials on equal rights, women and war, women in education, and women's liberation; organizations include the National Woman's Party, Women's Bureau of the U.S. Dept. of Labor, the International Federation of Business and Professional Women, and the National Organization of Women.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Blackwell, Henry Browne, 1825-1909; Stone, Lucy, 1818-1893; Hill, Clara M.; Kelly, Howard B.; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970
Organizations:
Vassar College; National American Woman Suffrage Association; Men's League for Woman Suffrage; Political Equality Association; National Woman's Party; International Federation of Business and Professional Women; National Organization for Women
Subjects:
Women in business; Women--Suffrage; Women in politics; Women social reformers; Women--Societies and clubs; Women's rights; Women and war; Women in education; Feminism; Women--Employment; Women in the professions; Feminists--United States
Places:
United States. Women's Bureau
Document Types:
Broadsides; Printed ephemera; Publications; Scrapbooks; Songs
VCL Categories:
Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, May 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of various donors, including Priscilla Leith (M2004-003).
Series List
- Series I. Woman Suffrage - General
- Series II. Woman Suffrage - Vassar College
- Series III. Women's Rights
Container List
- Series I. Woman Suffrage
  - Anti-suffrage material (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Men’s organizations for woman suffrage (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Petition to the New York State Assembly, signed by E. Cady Stanton, S.B. Anthony, Henry Blackwell, and Lucy Stone, on behalf of the American Equal Rights Association, 1866 Jan 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Facsimiles of suffrage broadsides (see also Folder 37), cartoons, and other materials (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Suffrage calendar, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Suffrage photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Suffrage plays (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Suffrage postcards (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Suffrage programs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Suffrage songs (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Suffrage stamps (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Solitude of Self, an address by E. Cady Stanton, 1892 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Suffrage speeches by Clara M. Hill (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Address by Dr. Howard B. Kelly given when presenting a medallion of Susan B. Anthony to Bryn Mawr College, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Germany (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Great Britain (see also Folder 39) (Box 1, Folders 15-17)
  - Great Britain: Women as Poor Law Guardians (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Italy (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Switzerland (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - United States (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - United States: Selections of U.S. government documents, 1887-1916 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association - catalogs and price lists, 1915-1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association. (Box 1, Folders 28-31)
  - Connecticut Woman Suffrage Association, New York State Woman Suffrage Party, Empire State Campaign Committee (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Men’s League for Woman Suffrage, Political Equality Association (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Woman’s Journal and American Suffrage Association (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous associations’ publications (Box 2, Folders 35-36)
  - Suffrage broadsides (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Suffrage band and banner (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Suffrage: Great Britain: Government reports, 1894, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Scrapbooks of suffrage-related clippings, 1906-1917; [2 scrapbooks] (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook enclosures, 1906-1917 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Votes for Women a Success," by the National American Woman Suffrage Association, undated (Mapcase, Drawer 23)
  - "The New York State Woman Suffrage Party - Educational Section,", [1920?] (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Series II. Woman Suffrage - Vassar College
  - General — includes prison notes of Elizabeth McShane Hilles, VC 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Suffrage Club (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - MacCracken correspondence, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - MacCracken correspondence, 1917-1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series III. Women's Rights
  - Miscellaneous printed material regarding equal rights for women, 1921-1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous items relating to and/or printed by the National Woman’s Party, 1920-1945, undated (Box 2, 43-46)
  - Miscellaneous publications regarding women and war (especially World War II), 1920-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the Woman’s Bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor regarding employment of women during World War II (Box 2, Folders 48-51)
  - First-day-of-issue stamp commemorating women in the armed forces, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the International Federation of Business and Professional Women, 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Materials relating to KNOW, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the International Council of Women, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the National Council of Women of the United States, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Materials relating to the National Organization for Women, 1955-1970 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Women’s Bibliography, by Joan Kelly-Gadol, Sarah Lawrence College, 1974 Fall (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Program and materials of the 55th Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, October 4-6, 1972: Women in Higher Education (Box 2, Folders 59-61)
  - Miscellaneous publications about women’s liberation (Box 3, Folders 62-66)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the National Organization for Women (NOW), 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folders 67-69)
  - Miscellaneous publications of the National Organization for Women (NOW) and other feminist organizations, circa 1974-1986 (Box 3, Folders 70-72)